Copilot actually changed my PR into an advertisement.
This is a real complaint that hit the top of Hacker News.
A developer only asked Copilot to fix a spelling error in his PR.
But after the fix, the code was fine, yet the PR footer had an extra line.
It read "Third-party product advertisement" with a link attached.
Even more bizarrely, the product was a "official partner" of Copilot.
So far, it was just absurd, but something even more explosive followed.
Someone searched for the exact ad copy and found nearly identical content.
It had already appeared in over 11,000 GitHub PRs.
The combined commits involved over 1.5 million PRs.
Not only GitHub, but also GitLab PRs were not spared.
Public opinion exploded. The poster said bluntly:
"I knew this kind of mess would happen sooner or later, but I didn't expect it so soon."
Some joked: "Forcing ads in is Microsoft's old habit."
They've been testing user limits since the Windows era.
Some media worried: if PR content with ads is used to train Copilot,
won't AI start pushing ads more and more frequently?
In the face of public backlash, the official response was firm.
They insisted GitHub will never place ads on its platform.
It was all a misunderstanding — Copilot only generated content with product prompts.
The system mistakenly inserted a recommendation prompt into the PR.
It looked like an ad, but it was essentially a product operation error.
It sounds reasonable, but it's hard to fully reassure people.
Because if you look deeper, the logic behind this incident is very realistic.
Both Copilot and the entire AI industry are facing the same problem: where does the money come from?
When the freemium model hits its ceiling, advertising monetization is almost unavoidable.
But this time, it doesn't appear in web sidebars or pop-ups.
Instead, it's directly embedded into the most trusted generated content.
That's why people reacted so strongly.
When AI starts inserting ads into answers, can you still trust it unconditionally?